<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Autopilot on HalfOnCloud</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/tags/autopilot/</link><description>Recent content in Autopilot on HalfOnCloud</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>2026 Radu Bogdan :: HalfOnCloud</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://halfoncloud.com/tags/autopilot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 8: Anatomy of a Failed Enrollment - Tracing an ESP Error from Screen to Root Cause</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-8-anatomy-of-a-failed-enrollment-tracing-an-esp-error-from-screen-to-root-cause/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-8-anatomy-of-a-failed-enrollment-tracing-an-esp-error-from-screen-to-root-cause/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="when-the-enrollment-status-page-fails"&gt;When the Enrollment Status Page Fails&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article picks up where &lt;a href="https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-7-intune-autopilot/"&gt;Part 7&lt;/a&gt; left off. If you followed that walkthrough, you have a working Autopilot deployment that registers devices, joins them to Entra ID and delivers apps through the Enrollment Status Page. This part covers what to do when that process breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Enrollment Status Page is the gatekeeper of Windows Autopilot. It tracks device preparation, device setup and account setup in sequence, holding the user at a progress screen until every assigned policy and application has been applied. When everything works, the user sees green checkmarks, login and lands on a configured desktop but when something fails, the ESP displays an error code and stops.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 7: Intune Autopilot Deployment Walkthrough</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-7-intune-autopilot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-7-intune-autopilot/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-windows-autopilot"&gt;What is Windows Autopilot?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This walkthrough assumes the tenant foundation is already in place. If you&amp;rsquo;re starting fresh &lt;a href="https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-6-intune-best-practices-device-management-foundations/"&gt;Part 6&lt;/a&gt; covers the enrollment controls, compliance baseline and ESP configuration that make this deployment easy to follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows Autopilot is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s cloud-based provisioning service that simplifies how organizations deploy Windows devices. Instead of manually imaging each endpoint, Autopilot leverages the factory installed Windows image and orchestrates device setup through Microsoft Intune and Microsoft Entra ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a user powers on a new device and connects to the internet, Autopilot takes over the Out-of-Box Experience, the device automatically joins Microsoft Entra ID, enrolls in Intune, receives assigned policies and applications and lands on a fully configured desktop, all without IT ever touching the hardware. OEMs and resellers can also register hardware hashes directly to an organization&amp;rsquo;s tenant, enabling true ship-to-user deployment scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>