<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EntraID on HalfOnCloud</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/tags/entraid/</link><description>Recent content in EntraID on HalfOnCloud</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>2026 Radu Bogdan :: HalfOnCloud</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://halfoncloud.com/tags/entraid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 7: Intune Autopilot Deployment Walkthrough</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-7-intune-autopilot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-7-intune-autopilot/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-windows-autopilot"&gt;What is Windows Autopilot?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This walkthrough assumes the tenant foundation is already in place. If you&amp;rsquo;re starting fresh &lt;a href="https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-6-intune-best-practices-device-management-foundations/"&gt;Part 6&lt;/a&gt; covers the enrollment controls, compliance baseline and ESP configuration that make this deployment easy to follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows Autopilot is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s cloud-based provisioning service that simplifies how organizations deploy Windows devices. Instead of manually imaging each endpoint, Autopilot leverages the factory installed Windows image and orchestrates device setup through Microsoft Intune and Microsoft Entra ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a user powers on a new device and connects to the internet, Autopilot takes over the Out-of-Box Experience, the device automatically joins Microsoft Entra ID, enrolls in Intune, receives assigned policies and applications and lands on a fully configured desktop, all without IT ever touching the hardware. OEMs and resellers can also register hardware hashes directly to an organization&amp;rsquo;s tenant, enabling true ship-to-user deployment scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 6: Building the Intune Foundation for Autopilot</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-6-intune-best-practices-device-management-foundations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-6-intune-best-practices-device-management-foundations/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="building-a-production-ready-intune-environment"&gt;Building a Production-Ready Intune Environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article walks through an Intune environment built in a small lab tenant. The focus is on the foundation that needs to be in place before Windows Autopilot can work reliably: tenant readiness, enrollment controls, device targeting, ESP behavior and a security baseline that holds up under real use. Everything shown reflects actual configuration, including what is enabled and how the pieces connect together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The environment is Windows-only and centered on User Driven Autopilot with Microsoft Entra join. The screenshots walk through tenant health, service connectors, dynamic device groups and Enrollment Status Page behavior along with a few optimizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 5: Conditional Access Policies</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-5-intune-conditional-access-policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-5-intune-conditional-access-policies/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-policy-dashboard"&gt;The Policy Dashboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Conditional Access policies described below represent a &lt;strong&gt;baseline&lt;/strong&gt; starting point for any tenant security. They are not a definitive or complete security model, but a minimal foundation that every tenant should have in place in some form. Whether you adopt these policies directly, adjust their scope or implement a variation that fits your environment, the key point is to &lt;strong&gt;start somewhere&lt;/strong&gt; rather than operate without core Conditional Access controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my tenant, I currently have &lt;strong&gt;8 Conditional Access policies&lt;/strong&gt; in total:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 Microsoft-managed (default policies)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 custom user-created policies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft-managed policies for &lt;strong&gt;blocking legacy authentication&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;requiring phishing-resistant MFA for administrators&lt;/strong&gt; are currently set to &lt;em&gt;Off&lt;/em&gt;. This is intentional, as I have implemented functionally equivalent policies with custom configurations tailored to my environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 4: Naming Conventions and Standards</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-4-intune-naming-conventions-and-standards/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-4-intune-naming-conventions-and-standards/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-naming-conventions-matter"&gt;Why Naming Conventions Matter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into &amp;ldquo;Conditional Access&amp;rdquo; policies and Intune configurations, I need to quickly explain the naming convention I use throughout my tenant. This might seem boring but getting this right early saves you a lot of trouble later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re new to Intune chances are your first policies will probably look similar to these ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#e7e9db;background-color:#2f1e2e;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"&gt;&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback"&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bitlocker Policy
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Win10 - Security Settings
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;GBL - W10 - Something - PRD
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;test policy delete later
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes they might get the job done quick but they lack to communicate purpose, scope or lifecycle, adding more only increases your technical debt.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 3: Entra ID Security Best Practices</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-3-entraid-security-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-3-entraid-security-best-practices/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="security-before-enrollment"&gt;Security Before Enrollment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users should have MFA configured before they enroll devices, &lt;strong&gt;Conditional Access&lt;/strong&gt; policies need to be in place before onboarding begins too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get this right and you have minor interruptions during onboarding, get it wrong and you&amp;rsquo;ll be fielding angry phone calls. This matches what I experienced in the past, having CA policies and authentication methods configured before Autopilot enrollment made the process smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-real-threat-landscape"&gt;The Real Threat Landscape&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft blocks an average of ~7,000 password attacks per second, Cyberattacks strike at an unprecedented scale, with Microsoft recording approximately ~600 million blocked threat attempts every 24 hours. This volume represents an increase in hostile actions, creating a threat environment where malicious packets slam into networks nearly every second.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Microsoft 365 Business Premium vs E3 vs E5</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-purchase-introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-purchase-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-question-everyone-asks"&gt;The Question Everyone Asks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start looking at Microsoft 365 subscriptions, the licensing matrix feels designed to confuse you. Business Premium, E3, E5, add-ons, standalone plans. Microsoft doesn&amp;rsquo;t make this easy, does it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a small business with 10 to 20 users, the question is straightforward: do you actually need E3 or E5, or is Business Premium enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After working with these plans and testing them in real environments, I can give you a direct answer. For most small businesses, Business Premium is not just enough. It&amp;rsquo;s the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-business-premium-actually-gives-you"&gt;What Business Premium Actually Gives You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business Premium is not a stripped-down version of the enterprise plans. It&amp;rsquo;s a complete package built specifically for small and medium businesses, with a cap at 300 users.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>