<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on HalfOnCloud</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on HalfOnCloud</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>2026 Radu Bogdan :: HalfOnCloud</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://halfoncloud.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 3: Entra ID Security Best Practices</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-3-entraid-security-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-3-entraid-security-best-practices/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="security-before-enrollment"&gt;Security Before Enrollment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users should have MFA configured before they enroll devices, &lt;strong&gt;Conditional Access&lt;/strong&gt; policies need to be in place before onboarding begins too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get this right and you have minor interruptions during onboarding, get it wrong and you&amp;rsquo;ll be fielding angry phone calls. This matches what I experienced in the past, having CA policies and authentication methods configured before Autopilot enrollment made the process smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-real-threat-landscape"&gt;The Real Threat Landscape&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft blocks an average of ~7,000 password attacks per second, Cyberattacks strike at an unprecedented scale, with Microsoft recording approximately ~600 million blocked threat attempts every 24 hours. This volume represents an increase in hostile actions, creating a threat environment where malicious packets slam into networks nearly every second.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 2: Configuring the new tenant</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-2-configuring-new-tenant/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-2-configuring-new-tenant/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="first-look-at-the-tenant"&gt;First Look at the Tenant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing the purchase and the initial MFA setup, you land in the Microsoft 365 admin center. First thing I did here was to check my Admin account under Users &amp;gt; Active users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything looks correct: Global Administrator role assigned, MFA configured, and the default HalfOnCloud.onmicrosoft.com domain attached to my account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://halfoncloud.com/images/Intune_P1_021.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="organization-settings"&gt;Organization Settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop is Settings &amp;gt; Org settings. This is where you configure tenant-wide options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three tabs here: Services, Security &amp;amp; privacy and Organization profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with &lt;strong&gt;Organization profile&lt;/strong&gt; to set the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://halfoncloud.com/images/Intune_P1_033.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="organization-information"&gt;Organization Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under Organization information, you set your technical contact. This is the email address that receives service notifications from Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 1: Purchase and Tenant Setup</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-purchase-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-purchase-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="choosing-the-right-plan"&gt;Choosing the Right Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft offers three main business tiers: Basic, Standard, and Premium. For this blog and my testing environment, I went with &amp;ldquo;Business Premium&amp;rdquo; because it&amp;rsquo;s the only one that includes Intune and Entra ID P1. If you need device management and Conditional Access, the other two won&amp;rsquo;t cut it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pricing shows $22/user/month for annual billing. I started with monthly to test things out first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://halfoncloud.com/images/Intune_P1_000.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="real-world-pricing-in-europe"&gt;Real World Pricing in Europe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft publishes prices in USD, but if you&amp;rsquo;re in Europe you pay in local currency plus VAT, the difference is significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m based in Romania, so here&amp;rsquo;s what the actual costs look like in my region:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Microsoft 365 Business Premium vs E3 vs E5</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-purchase-introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-purchase-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-question-everyone-asks"&gt;The Question Everyone Asks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start looking at Microsoft 365 subscriptions, the licensing matrix feels designed to confuse you. Business Premium, E3, E5, add-ons, standalone plans. Microsoft doesn&amp;rsquo;t make this easy, does it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a small business with 10 to 20 users, the question is straightforward: do you actually need E3 or E5, or is Business Premium enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After working with these plans and testing them in real environments, I can give you a direct answer. For most small businesses, Business Premium is not just enough. It&amp;rsquo;s the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-business-premium-actually-gives-you"&gt;What Business Premium Actually Gives You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business Premium is not a stripped-down version of the enterprise plans. It&amp;rsquo;s a complete package built specifically for small and medium businesses, with a cap at 300 users.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Welcome to HalfOnCloud</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/welcome-to-halfoncloud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/welcome-to-halfoncloud/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="who-i-am"&gt;Who I Am&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Radu, an IT professional working mostly with Microsoft technologies. My days are spent somewhere between on-prem infrastructure and cloud services, which is exactly where the name &amp;ldquo;HalfOnCloud&amp;rdquo; comes from. Not fully in the cloud, not stuck in the past but somewhere in between, like most real environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main areas are Microsoft SCCM/ConfigMgr, Intune, Azure, Entra ID and Microsoft 365. I also work with VMware for virtualization and PowerShell for pretty much everything else. If it can be automated I&amp;rsquo;ll definetely try to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-this-blog-is"&gt;What This Blog Is&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t a polished knowledge base or a collection of perfect tutorials. It&amp;rsquo;s more like my technical journal, a place where I document what I learn, what breaks and what actually works in production.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>