<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MSIntune on HalfOnCloud</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/tags/msintune/</link><description>Recent content in MSIntune on HalfOnCloud</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>2026 Radu Bogdan :: HalfOnCloud</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://halfoncloud.com/tags/msintune/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 8: Anatomy of a Failed Enrollment - Tracing an ESP Error from Screen to Root Cause</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-8-anatomy-of-a-failed-enrollment-tracing-an-esp-error-from-screen-to-root-cause/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-8-anatomy-of-a-failed-enrollment-tracing-an-esp-error-from-screen-to-root-cause/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="when-the-enrollment-status-page-fails"&gt;When the Enrollment Status Page Fails&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article picks up where &lt;a href="https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-7-intune-autopilot/"&gt;Part 7&lt;/a&gt; left off. If you followed that walkthrough, you have a working Autopilot deployment that registers devices, joins them to Entra ID and delivers apps through the Enrollment Status Page. This part covers what to do when that process breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Enrollment Status Page is the gatekeeper of Windows Autopilot. It tracks device preparation, device setup and account setup in sequence, holding the user at a progress screen until every assigned policy and application has been applied. When everything works, the user sees green checkmarks, login and lands on a configured desktop but when something fails, the ESP displays an error code and stops.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 7: Intune Autopilot Deployment Walkthrough</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-7-intune-autopilot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-7-intune-autopilot/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-windows-autopilot"&gt;What is Windows Autopilot?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This walkthrough assumes the tenant foundation is already in place. If you&amp;rsquo;re starting fresh &lt;a href="https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-6-intune-best-practices-device-management-foundations/"&gt;Part 6&lt;/a&gt; covers the enrollment controls, compliance baseline and ESP configuration that make this deployment easy to follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows Autopilot is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s cloud-based provisioning service that simplifies how organizations deploy Windows devices. Instead of manually imaging each endpoint, Autopilot leverages the factory installed Windows image and orchestrates device setup through Microsoft Intune and Microsoft Entra ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a user powers on a new device and connects to the internet, Autopilot takes over the Out-of-Box Experience, the device automatically joins Microsoft Entra ID, enrolls in Intune, receives assigned policies and applications and lands on a fully configured desktop, all without IT ever touching the hardware. OEMs and resellers can also register hardware hashes directly to an organization&amp;rsquo;s tenant, enabling true ship-to-user deployment scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 6: Building the Intune Foundation for Autopilot</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-6-intune-best-practices-device-management-foundations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-6-intune-best-practices-device-management-foundations/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="building-a-production-ready-intune-environment"&gt;Building a Production-Ready Intune Environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article walks through an Intune environment built in a small lab tenant. The focus is on the foundation that needs to be in place before Windows Autopilot can work reliably: tenant readiness, enrollment controls, device targeting, ESP behavior and a security baseline that holds up under real use. Everything shown reflects actual configuration, including what is enabled and how the pieces connect together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The environment is Windows-only and centered on User Driven Autopilot with Microsoft Entra join. The screenshots walk through tenant health, service connectors, dynamic device groups and Enrollment Status Page behavior along with a few optimizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Apps Deployment with PowerShell Installer &amp; Delivery Optimization Gotchas</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/powershell-script-installer-for-win32-part2-m365-apps-and-delivery-optimization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/powershell-script-installer-for-win32-part2-m365-apps-and-delivery-optimization/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="building-on-the-foundation"&gt;Building on the Foundation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my previous article, &lt;em&gt;PowerShell script installer for Win32 apps Guide&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve demonstrated Microsoft’s new native PowerShell installer type for Win32 apps using a simple 7-Zip MSI deployment. That approach removed the need to repackage applications just to adjust install logic, a meaningful improvement to the Win32 app workflow in Intune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, 7-Zip is a small self-contained installer, the real test comes when applying this same approach to a much more complex scenario: an application that downloads several gigabytes of content from a CDN during installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article takes the PowerShell installer model to the next level with &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft 365 Apps&lt;/strong&gt;, an evergreen deployment that pulls the latest Monthly Enterprise Channel build directly from Microsoft’s CDN. Along the way I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that my existing Delivery Optimization (DO) policy was also actively interfering with the install, silently throttling download speed and turning what should have been a ~15–20 minute deployment into a multi-hour experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 5: Conditional Access Policies</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-5-intune-conditional-access-policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-5-intune-conditional-access-policies/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-policy-dashboard"&gt;The Policy Dashboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Conditional Access policies described below represent a &lt;strong&gt;baseline&lt;/strong&gt; starting point for any tenant security. They are not a definitive or complete security model, but a minimal foundation that every tenant should have in place in some form. Whether you adopt these policies directly, adjust their scope or implement a variation that fits your environment, the key point is to &lt;strong&gt;start somewhere&lt;/strong&gt; rather than operate without core Conditional Access controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my tenant, I currently have &lt;strong&gt;8 Conditional Access policies&lt;/strong&gt; in total:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 Microsoft-managed (default policies)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 custom user-created policies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft-managed policies for &lt;strong&gt;blocking legacy authentication&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;requiring phishing-resistant MFA for administrators&lt;/strong&gt; are currently set to &lt;em&gt;Off&lt;/em&gt;. This is intentional, as I have implemented functionally equivalent policies with custom configurations tailored to my environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerShell script installer for Win32 apps Guide</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/powershell-script-for-intune-win32-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/powershell-script-for-intune-win32-apps/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-new-way"&gt;The New Way&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been packaging Win32 apps for Intune for years using the classic approach: wrap everything into an &lt;code&gt;.intunewin&lt;/code&gt; file, include the PowerShell install script and call it from the command line. It works but it has a cost, any small change in the script means a full repackage, re-upload and another round of content processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently Microsoft recently introduced a quiet but significant change: &lt;strong&gt;PowerShell Script as a native installer type&lt;/strong&gt; for Win32 apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this model, the script is no longer embedded inside the encrypted payload, it lives as editable metadata in Intune similar to detection rules. That means no more rebuilding packages just to fix a typo or add a switch like &lt;code&gt;/norestart&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Intune Declarative Device Management (DDM) Guide</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/microsoft-intune-declarative-device-management-ddm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/microsoft-intune-declarative-device-management-ddm/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background-and-intent"&gt;Background and Intent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Declarative Device Management (DDM) represents a fundamental architectural shift in how Microsoft Intune manages devices. This article brings those pieces together, it combines verified information with hands-on testing performed on a Windows 11 25H2 virtual machine, along with practical PowerShell checks you can use to validate DDM behavior on real devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus is on Windows (MMP-C / WinDC), while also highlighting where the Windows implementation differs from other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="short-summary"&gt;Short Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you only need the essentials:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traditional management (OMA-DM)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Intune continuously pushes settings to the device on a schedule, the device applies them, waits and receives the same instructions again at the next sync.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 4: Naming Conventions and Standards</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-4-intune-naming-conventions-and-standards/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-4-intune-naming-conventions-and-standards/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-naming-conventions-matter"&gt;Why Naming Conventions Matter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into &amp;ldquo;Conditional Access&amp;rdquo; policies and Intune configurations, I need to quickly explain the naming convention I use throughout my tenant. This might seem boring but getting this right early saves you a lot of trouble later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re new to Intune chances are your first policies will probably look similar to these ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#e7e9db;background-color:#2f1e2e;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"&gt;&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback"&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bitlocker Policy
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Win10 - Security Settings
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;GBL - W10 - Something - PRD
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="display:flex;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;test policy delete later
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes they might get the job done quick but they lack to communicate purpose, scope or lifecycle, adding more only increases your technical debt.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 3: Entra ID Security Best Practices</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-3-entraid-security-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-3-entraid-security-best-practices/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="security-before-enrollment"&gt;Security Before Enrollment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users should have MFA configured before they enroll devices, &lt;strong&gt;Conditional Access&lt;/strong&gt; policies need to be in place before onboarding begins too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get this right and you have minor interruptions during onboarding, get it wrong and you&amp;rsquo;ll be fielding angry phone calls. This matches what I experienced in the past, having CA policies and authentication methods configured before Autopilot enrollment made the process smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-real-threat-landscape"&gt;The Real Threat Landscape&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft blocks an average of ~7,000 password attacks per second, Cyberattacks strike at an unprecedented scale, with Microsoft recording approximately ~600 million blocked threat attempts every 24 hours. This volume represents an increase in hostile actions, creating a threat environment where malicious packets slam into networks nearly every second.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 2: Configuring the new tenant</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-2-configuring-new-tenant/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-part-2-configuring-new-tenant/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="first-look-at-the-tenant"&gt;First Look at the Tenant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing the purchase and the initial MFA setup, you land in the Microsoft 365 admin center. First thing I did here was to check my Admin account under Users &amp;gt; Active users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything looks correct: Global Administrator role assigned, MFA configured, and the default HalfOnCloud.onmicrosoft.com domain attached to my account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://halfoncloud.com/images/Intune_P1_021.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="organization-settings"&gt;Organization Settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop is Settings &amp;gt; Org settings. This is where you configure tenant-wide options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three tabs here: Services, Security &amp;amp; privacy and Organization profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with &lt;strong&gt;Organization profile&lt;/strong&gt; to set the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://halfoncloud.com/images/Intune_P1_033.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="organization-information"&gt;Organization Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under Organization information, you set your technical contact. This is the email address that receives service notifications from Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>M365 Business Premium Part 1: Purchase and Tenant Setup</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-purchase-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-purchase-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="choosing-the-right-plan"&gt;Choosing the Right Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft offers three main business tiers: Basic, Standard, and Premium. For this blog and my testing environment, I went with &amp;ldquo;Business Premium&amp;rdquo; because it&amp;rsquo;s the only one that includes Intune and Entra ID P1. If you need device management and Conditional Access, the other two won&amp;rsquo;t cut it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pricing shows $22/user/month for annual billing. I started with monthly to test things out first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://halfoncloud.com/images/Intune_P1_000.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="real-world-pricing-in-europe"&gt;Real World Pricing in Europe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft publishes prices in USD, but if you&amp;rsquo;re in Europe you pay in local currency plus VAT, the difference is significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m based in Romania, so here&amp;rsquo;s what the actual costs look like in my region:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Microsoft 365 Business Premium vs E3 vs E5</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-purchase-introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/m365-business-premium-purchase-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-question-everyone-asks"&gt;The Question Everyone Asks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start looking at Microsoft 365 subscriptions, the licensing matrix feels designed to confuse you. Business Premium, E3, E5, add-ons, standalone plans. Microsoft doesn&amp;rsquo;t make this easy, does it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a small business with 10 to 20 users, the question is straightforward: do you actually need E3 or E5, or is Business Premium enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After working with these plans and testing them in real environments, I can give you a direct answer. For most small businesses, Business Premium is not just enough. It&amp;rsquo;s the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-business-premium-actually-gives-you"&gt;What Business Premium Actually Gives You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business Premium is not a stripped-down version of the enterprise plans. It&amp;rsquo;s a complete package built specifically for small and medium businesses, with a cap at 300 users.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>