<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Win32 on HalfOnCloud</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/tags/win32/</link><description>Recent content in Win32 on HalfOnCloud</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>2026 Radu Bogdan :: HalfOnCloud</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://halfoncloud.com/tags/win32/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>M365 Apps Deployment with PowerShell Installer &amp; Delivery Optimization Gotchas</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/powershell-script-installer-for-win32-part2-m365-apps-and-delivery-optimization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/powershell-script-installer-for-win32-part2-m365-apps-and-delivery-optimization/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="building-on-the-foundation"&gt;Building on the Foundation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my previous article, &lt;em&gt;PowerShell script installer for Win32 apps Guide&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve demonstrated Microsoft’s new native PowerShell installer type for Win32 apps using a simple 7-Zip MSI deployment. That approach removed the need to repackage applications just to adjust install logic, a meaningful improvement to the Win32 app workflow in Intune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, 7-Zip is a small self-contained installer, the real test comes when applying this same approach to a much more complex scenario: an application that downloads several gigabytes of content from a CDN during installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article takes the PowerShell installer model to the next level with &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft 365 Apps&lt;/strong&gt;, an evergreen deployment that pulls the latest Monthly Enterprise Channel build directly from Microsoft’s CDN. Along the way I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that my existing Delivery Optimization (DO) policy was also actively interfering with the install, silently throttling download speed and turning what should have been a ~15–20 minute deployment into a multi-hour experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerShell script installer for Win32 apps Guide</title><link>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/powershell-script-for-intune-win32-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://halfoncloud.com/posts/powershell-script-for-intune-win32-apps/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-new-way"&gt;The New Way&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been packaging Win32 apps for Intune for years using the classic approach: wrap everything into an &lt;code&gt;.intunewin&lt;/code&gt; file, include the PowerShell install script and call it from the command line. It works but it has a cost, any small change in the script means a full repackage, re-upload and another round of content processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently Microsoft recently introduced a quiet but significant change: &lt;strong&gt;PowerShell Script as a native installer type&lt;/strong&gt; for Win32 apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this model, the script is no longer embedded inside the encrypted payload, it lives as editable metadata in Intune similar to detection rules. That means no more rebuilding packages just to fix a typo or add a switch like &lt;code&gt;/norestart&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>